

# Nadezhda Sitdikova

# **Profile**

I help users to have the best possible experience interacting with their data by leveraging available tools and creating a meaningful data foundation. This includes comprehensive analysis, improving data quality, data availability and integrity, as well as visualization and user-friendly interface development.

### **Contacts**

**Phone** 

+49 176 35706859

**Email** 

nadezhda.sitdikova.de@gmail.com

Address

71063 Sindelfingen, Germany

# **Expertise**

**JavaScript** 

Python

SOL

Git

Agile

Qlik

### Languages

**English** 

Full Professional Proficiency

German

Limited Working Proficiency

Russian

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

## Work experience

#### February 2023-March 2024

Siemens AG I Erlangen, Germany

#### **Data Analyst & Data Architecture (Working Student)**

- Contributed to sales analytics initiatives, driving the development of data products that provided actionable insights and improved decision-making.
- Analyzed and consolidated multiple sales-related data sources, delivering comprehensive reports that improved data availability and alignment across the organization within an agile framework.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, providing expert support on data analysis, cleansing, and visualization.
- Developed Qlik applications to streamline data analysis and visualization.

#### February 2020–September 2021

Individual entrepreneur I Moscow, Russia

#### **Project manager**

- Led cross-functional teams up to 6 members, ensuring timely delivery of customized solutions that met client requirements.
- Performed in-depth analysis and optimization of customer business processes, identifying inefficiencies and driving process improvements that increased operational efficiency by 60%.
- Implemented digital data flows automation using Python and JavaScript, reducing manual tasks by 4 hours per week and enhancing workflow accuracy and speed.
- Integrated APIs to streamline data flow, improving system integration, reducing data processing time by 30%, and ensuring seamless connectivity across platforms.

#### September 2018-January 2020

Lexema I Ufa, Russia

#### **Development engineer**

- Analyzed and modeled customer business processes to identify inefficiencies, bottlenecks, and areas for improvement, resulting in a 60% increase in process efficiency.
- Designed and implemented optimized data flows and algorithms, automating key business processes and reducing manual workload by 40%, leading to a reduction in operational errors by 90%.
- Delivered tailored support to end-users and customers through detailed reports, presentations, and interactive training sessions, improving user adoption rates and reducing post-deployment support issues.

### **Education**

Q 2021 - 2023

TU Ilmenau

#### M.Sc. Research in Computer and System Engineering

Master-Thesis: Parasite Classification and Weakly Supervised Detection in Bee Images

O 2013 - 2018

Ufa State Aviation Technical University

#### **B.Sc. Applied Computer Science**

Bachelor-Thesis: Automated system for calculation and evaluation of energy consumption